Marina Lapteva

+386 696-77-216 | marina.lapteva@hotmail.com | linkedin.com/in/marina-lapteva | github.com/LMV5 | My Portfolio

Frontend Developer

Summary

A frontend developer focusing on React and Next.js. I'm open to learning new technologies despite this. I'm motivated to learn and grow in this dynamic field. It's great to see the immediate results of my work. I'm ensure that my banking experience, teamwork skills, problem-solving ability, and readiness for change will help me in this new position.

Technical Skills

Frontend development: HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, React, Redux, React Query, Next.js, REST API Other: Git, VITE, MongoDB

PROJECTS

A-Rent | Tailwind, Next.js, REST API, MongoDB, Mongoose, NextAuth.js, Cloudinary

- Developed A-Rent web application that enables property owners to list rental properties by providing detailed information and manage reservations.
- Users can sign up with Google account, can add properties to their bookmarks and share property listings via social media platforms like Facebook, Twitter, Telegram, and through email.

Notes App | React, Tailwind, TypeScript

• Created a simple React application for creating and deleting notes.

Weather App | HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript

- Created weather web application using SASS and media queries for responsive design
- Used API for fetching data based on user input.

Experience

Senior specialist

December 2017 – August 2019

Sberbank (Banking, Operations and Administration Department)

 $Chelyabinsk,\ Russia$

- Created and implemented instructional materials, helping employees of related departments.
- Organized meetings, conferences, seminars, and sports events for the bank's branch, ensuring smooth execution and participant satisfaction.

Head of Department

May 2016 – December 2017

Sberbank (Banking, Operations and Administration Department)

Chelyabinsk, Russia

- Enforced a change in outgoing correspondence routes, reducing shipments from three per week to one, leading to an annual savings of €15,000.
- Developed and implemented together with the IT department a new system for document search using barcodes within the bank's internal system. This change has resulted in a 50% reduction in search time. This means employees saved approximately 8% of their work hours per week, which is especially helpful for those who often need to find documents quickly.
- Optimized outgoing bank correspondence by reducing the amount of registered letters that need special notifications. This change saved at least $\mathfrak{C}3,000$ every year.
- Helped new employees fit in at the company by showing them how things work, what we do, and what's expected from them. This made it easier for them to become part of the team quickly.

Specialist

November 2014 – May 2016

Sberbank (Banking, Operations and Administration Department)

Chelyabinsk, Russia

• Managed collegial bodies, making sure everyone communicated well and decisions were made efficiently. This helped us to cut down the time it took to approve decisions from 72 hours to 36 hours.

EDUCATION